Matthew Brozen

Los Angeles, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Matthew-Brozen/763b7179e3f8003a

2 years experience working as a web developer. Looking for work as a junior or mid level developer. Previously working for BRE Investment as a web developer doing MEAN stack software development and then doing freelance web development and tutoring computer science. Before that I was pursuing a career in urban planning but decided that my skills and abilities are best suited for computer science. I have experience and skill in Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Node, Express, Mongo, Angular, Heroku, Firebase and bring a detailed understanding of data structures, discrete mathematics and programming logic to any development team. Graduate of General Assembly's Web Development Immersive, A.A. in Computer Science from Los Angeles City College, B.S. in urban studies from University of Minnesota.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Los Angeles, CA - September 2015 to Present

-Sole Developer working on a variety of projects and technologies with a focus on full stack javascript web applications and noSQL API's. Complete Project and Client list available upon request. Summary of services are below:

- Front End Development
- -Angular.js
- -Angular 2
- -Vanilla HTML, CSS and Javascript
- -Bootstrap
- -Adobe
- -React
- -HTML5
- -CSS3
- -ES6
- Back End Development
- -Primarily focused on Mongo Express and Node Javascript based NoSQL API's
- -Also proficient in SQL API's with Rails, Postgres, sqlite and oracle
- Version Control
- -Git
- -Github
- -Stash
- Testing
- -Mocha
- -Chai
- -Supertest
- -Browserstack
- Deployment

- -Heroku
- -AWS
- -Firebase
- -Jenkins
- -Travis
- -Hosting on Google
- Agile Development
- -Scrum
- -Lean
- -Slack
- -Jira
- -Trello
- Full Stack Development
- -Primary focused on MEAN stack; Mongo, Express, Angular and Node
- -Proficient in Ruby on Rails, Java and Oracle
- Client List
- -Silverback Ink
- -Ventura ESOP
- -MW Designs
- -Studio Eighteen
- -Full Family Tree
- -Spirit of the Pony Express
- -Who's Got Game
- -Taproot Research Inc.

Web Developer

Genesis Global - Los Angeles, CA - April 2017 to July 2017

Three Month Contract Position

- -Onsite and Remote
- Angular 2 Development
- -Turning jQuery plugins into reusable Angular directives
- Bootstrap 4 Development
- -Updating bootstrap 3 to bootstrap 4
- -Turning templates into custom reusable components
- Website Development
- -HTML5, CSS3 and ES6
- Delivering Proof of Concepts for front end interfaces and Sentiment Analysis API integration
- Watson API integration using Mongo, Express, Node, Chai, Mocha, Supertest and deployed to Heroku
- ♠ Aylien Public News API integration using Mongo, Express, Node, Chai, Mocha, Supertest and deployed to Heroku

Version control using Git and Stash

Lead Web Developer

BRE Investments - Los Angeles, CA - October 2016 to December 2016

Leading a three person MEAN stack development team; organizing development team, delegating development

tasks, reviewing code, coaching developers and supervising performance for client.

● Planning Project Sprint; Wireframes, Trello, bootstrap, building MVP, design UI/UX, interfacing with the client,

building project to client spec, version control using git and github, and testing with; Chai, Mocha and Supertest

- Full stack web development in Javascript
- -HTML5
- -CSS3
- -ES6
- Lead designer and developer ValueEgg
- -Web Application for online appraisals
- -Angular front end, NoSQL mongodb backend, Node server with express router
- -Bootstrap design framework
- -Google maps API place autocomplete
- -Twilio Integration instant text messaging
- Sole designer and developer EvilRent
- -Web Application for checking if your apartment is rent controlled
- -Angular front end, NoSQL mongodb backend, Node server with express router
- -Bootstrap design framework
- -Google maps API place autocomplete

Tutor

Los Angeles Community College District - Los Angeles, CA - January 2016 to June 2016

Tutoring Computer Science students: Three times a week for four hour sessions.

- Topics include; Windows OS, Visual Basic, Java, C++, and SQL.
- Tracking tutor hours for all tutors: Filing hours with administration and auditing hours.

EDUCATION

A.A. in Computer Science

Los Angeles City College 2014 to 2016

B.S. in Urban Studies

University of Minnesota 2006 to 2011

SKILLS

BOOTSTRAP (2 years), Git (2 years), HTML5 (2 years), JAVA (2 years), JAVASCRIPT (2 years)

LINKS

http://www.matthewbrozen.com